We established earlier that MAC tables store the information needed to direct traffic from a switch to a device.
When a device connects to a switch, the MAC address of that device is learned.
This way, if another device transmits data, the switch does one of two things: either it knows the MAC address of the destination and sends the data there,
or it floods the data out of the other ports to the other devices to find out which device has the destination MAC address.
As far as transmitting the actual data, switches use two main methods for doing so. Store-and-forward—this is an older method of sending data.
Basically, a switch will receive a data frame in its entirety, check for errors, and then forward the frame.
While this is reliable, it is also slower, as a frame isn't sent until its entire contents have been received and checked.
The other and newer switch type is the cut-through method.
In this method, a switch just needs to know the frame header that has the destination MAC address and then it sends the frame.
While this is faster, this doesn't check for errors, so corrupt data frames can be sent, which are then just discarded at the destination.